现在联上线了
Now they're on-line.
这个会伪装成Marlo的电话?
This is masked as Marlo's cell number?
到底是怎么弄的 什么原理
How the fuck? How?
冒名仿制通讯流 就跟通讯公司的交换机似的
Spoofed to imitate a call stream like it's a phone-company switch.
可以往里输入任何我们想要的数位码
We can put any digits in we want.
同时 通讯公司的案内文件 会记录下我们给Sydnor打的电话
Meanwhile, phone company paperwork on the case has the cell we gave to Sydnor.
都是些相当基础的玩意儿
It's fairly basic shit.
现在 千万照着剧本念  咱们可不能露出任何马脚
Now, stick to the script. We don't want any tell-tales.
就算用了变声器也一样
Even with the voice modulator,
你是完全曝光在外
you're exposed here.
7-B-14
Seven-Baker-14.
这里是总台 14号请讲
BGA. Go ahead, 14.
这里是14号 我看到有辆车堵住了入口
14. I got a vehicle blocking an entrance.
在Pressman街400号
400 Pressman.
搞什么
What the...
妈的
Shit.
- Templeton - 喂你这家伙
- Templeton. - Hey, you...
你打哪儿想出来的 你这变态神经病
Where do you get off, you sick little twist?
性? 我对他们下手跟性没关系 我没有性虐他们
Sexual? I'm not sexual with them, I'm not abusive with them.
你根本不了解我 怎么敢在报纸上胡写乱写
How dare you write that in your paper without knowing nothing about me?
- 什么 - 咬可不是性 咬就是咬
- What? - Biting's not sex, it's biting.
我还没那么变态
I'm not sick like that.
别挂 别挂 别挂
Hang on, hang on, hang on.
也许我该来咬咬你
Maybe I should come bite you.
你想试试么 Scotty
Would you like that, Scotty?
我看你想要得很呐 对不对
I bet you would like that. Am I right?
你把我写成个变态
You write about me like I'm sick.
你自己才是变态的那个 知道吗
You're the sick one, you know that?
所以你才喜欢我嘛 Scotty 是不是这个原因
Is that why you like me, Scotty? Is that why?
我操
Fuck me.
是 我是Holley 巴尔的摩警署凶杀组
Yeah, this is Holley, Baltimore Homicide.
我需要追踪一通与08H114案件有关的电话
I need a trap-and-trace on case 08H114.
这电话正在通话
Cell phone is in use right now.
Scotty
我可以来咬咬你 你看看是不是很有快感
I could come bite you, you tell me how sexual it is.
好说 别挂 你是...你在哪儿
OK, hang on. Who... Where are you?
现在这么办
Here's what's happening now.
你这样羞辱我
You humiliate me like that?
在我父亲
You mortify me like that in front of my father?
和我父亲的父亲面前让我难堪
My father's father?
给我听着 你这吸毒佬疯癫佬
Listen to me, smack daddy, crack daddy,
虐待小孩的变态佬 以后咱这么办
little baby whack daddy, here's what's happening.
你再也找不到他们了
You ain't never going to find them anymore.
再也看不到他们了
You ain't never gonna see them no more.
我现在给你发个东西  你给我好好看看这家伙
I'm sending you something right now. You take a good look at this guy,
因为你以后再也见不着他了
because you ain't never going to see him no more.
好吧
Hey, OK.
别挂电话 我们能...
Don't hang up. Can we...
糟糕 你打通McNulty没
Oh, shit. Did you get McNulty?
- 只有语音信箱 - 老天爷
- Just his voicemail. - Oh, Christ.
那是....那就是他
That was... That was him.
又是他
Again!
巴尔的摩腔很纯正嘛
Nice Bawlmer accent.
我的独门绝活
It's my heritage.
...追踪嫌犯电话来自普拉特街五号码头
...has traced the phone in question to Pier Five on Pratt Street.
所有小队都赶往附近 捉拿现场所有人
All units respond to that 20 and detain anyone present
当值警官取决于到达顺序
pending the arrival of a duty officer.
这里是1组10号 收到 我正往那边去
One-Baker-Ten, copy that. I'm rolling.
这里是1组13号 我就要到了
One-Baker-13, I'm almost there.
所有分队注意
KGA to all units.
要找的是名正在用手机 年龄在10至30岁之间的男子
Be advised that we're looking for a 10-30 individual on a cell phone.
- 有看到人打电话吗 - 我是没看到
- Anyone on a phone? - Not that I saw.
只是些来来往往的人 谁都有可能
Just people moving through, it could be anybody.
大伙先散开 把这些人的名字都记下
Let's just fan out and take names.
沿着这条路 把那些人的名字都记下
Go down this road. Get their names over there.
把这片区域的人聚集在一起
Get everybody up in this area now.
- 住手 - 这是在干嘛
- Stop. - What the hell is this?
- 嘿 放开我 - 举起手来
- Hey, let go of me. - Get your hands up.
趴在地上 举起手来 下车
Get on the ground now. Get your hands up! Step out!
把那边的人都抓起来 收缴他们的手机
Get everybody over there and get their cell phones.
每个人都掏出手机放在桌上
Everyone take out your cell phones and place them on the table in front of you.
住手 他什么都没做
Stop, he didn't do anything.
你们在干嘛
What are you doing?
空巡呼叫总部 这里的情况我盯着
Foxtrot to KGA, I'm your eyeball.
- 长官 我们找到他了 - 放屁
- Sarge, we got him. - Bullshit.
- 我录下了他的电话 - 那傻逼还真打了电话么
- I got him on tape. - The goof actually called.
对对 正中下怀
Yeah, yeah, it was sweet.
嘿 我错过了啥好戏
Hey, what'd I miss?
他扯了一堆题外话 说他想咬我
He went off on a tangent. Said he wanted to bite me.
什么 怎么咬你
What? Bite you how?
Scott 你是说他威胁你...
Scott, are you saying that he threatened to...
请稍等 别挂
Wait a minute. Hold on a second.
老天
Holy Christ.
* When you walk through the garden *
火线重案组 第五季 第7集
the wire s05ep07
* you gotta watch your back *
* well I beg your pardon *
* walk the straight and narrow track *
* if you walk with Jesus *
* he's gonna save your soul *
* you gotta keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
* he's got the fire and the fury *
* at his command *
* well you don't have to worry *
* if you hold on to Jesus hand *
* we'll all be safe from Satan *
* when the thunder rolls *
* just gotta help me keep the devil *
* way down in the hole *
反正法学院里可没教过这个 -Pearlman
那咱们以后就是合作关系了?
So are we partners or what?
不 Clay 你没把我的费用付掉前
No, Clay. I don't pick so much as a single juror
别指望我给你选一个陪审员
without the full amount of my fee being paid.
如果你想Billy Murphy接你的案子
If you want Billy Murphy on your case,
就得先把钱交足
you got to pay to put him there.
我已经给你尝了甜头了 5位数的甜头
I got a taste for you right up front. A good, five-figure taste.
但你要我现在就提前 给你付清大获全胜的钱
But you asking for me to pay a winner's fee right up front,
你知道 我还没赢呢
and you know what? I ain't a winner yet.
现在我的前途岌岌可危
Right now, with the sword hanging over my head,
没有以往我所依赖的
I don't have the kind of financial support at my disposal
可供我任意支配的经济来源 你懂没
that I would ordinarily be able to rely upon, you feel?
那些个金主们都收手了?
So the money boys are laying off, huh?
那些家伙都是鼠目寸光
They thinkin' short when they should be thinkin' long.
真他妈可耻
Shameful shit.
给你两万五 等你选完评审团再给你两万五
25,000, 25,000 more when you seat a jury.
这个在我这里行不通
I don't work that way.
我知道行不通 伙伴 我知道行不通
I know you don't, partner, I know you don't.
我还做梦都没想过会求你出庭
And normally I wouldn't dream of asking you to suit up for game day
帮我打官司
with my tab as it is.
20万我帮你脱身
200,000 when I get you out from under this mess.
还有 Clay 别玩儿我
And, Clay, don't fuck me.
这笔钱你他妈想都别想浑水摸鱼
Don't even think about fucking me out of a single part of that fee.
Billy 你还不了解我吗
Oh, Billy, you talk as if you don't know me.
我太失望了 失望透顶
I'm disappointed. I am.
老兄 咱们公平点
My brother, let's be fair.
我这可是给你提供了个
I'm providing you with the opportunity
跟州检查官面对面交手的机会
to go head-to-head with the state's attorney
还是个风口浪尖的案子
in a case that's gonna be front-page news.
这种抛头露面的大好机会
For all that profile?
妈的 伙伴 你给我钱还差不多
Shit, partner, you should be payin' me a fee.
说真的 哥们  要是给我的竞选委员会送个两万
Seriously, dawg, for 20,000 cash to my campaign committee,
我就是被联邦政府起诉  也让你给我打官司
I'll get myself indicted federal, let you go to trial on that.
虐联邦政府就跟虐小孩似的 绝对让你声名鹊起
Beat the feds like a stepchild, an' really make a name for yourself.
玩儿你 不 老兄 我是要捧你
Fuck you? Naw, son, I'm gonna make you.
Johnnie Cochran: 美国著名律师 辛普森案辩护律师之一
那些傻叉转眼就会把 Johnnie Cochran忘得一干二净
Motherfuckers gonna be wipin' they ass with Johnnie Cochran's memory,
腆着脸把你的名片当宝
and carryin' your business card in every damn pocket before we done.
不必 我的名气已经够大了
No. I already got more rep than any lawyer would ever need.
你的舌绽莲花留到上庭再用如何
Why don't you save that silver-tongued bullshit for the jury?
好的
Right.
不 后来就没收到了
No, nothing since.
好的
All right.
我 Barlow和Kincaid一直守在这儿
Me, Barlow and Kincaid been sittin' here
跟美泰克电器修理工似的 等得花儿都谢了
like the fucking Maytag repairmen, growing piles.
什么都没有 连通电话都没 然后突然
Nothing, not a call. Then, bang.
港口什么都没查到
No luck at the harbor.
我们跟踪GPS信号 结果一无所获 就在五号码头那边
We were tracking the GPS then it just goes dead. Area of Pier Five.
- McNulty在哪儿 - 去报社了
- Where's McNulty? - Over at the newspaper.
再把那个混蛋的声音放来听听
Let's hear that motherfucker again.
喂你这家伙 你打哪儿出来的 你这变态神经病
Hey, you, where do you get off, you sick little twist?
听上去像来自Dundalk的宅男 (马里兰中部城镇)
Sounds like some gearhead from Dundalk.
他情绪听起来怎么样
And emotionally, how was he?
- 听上去很生气 - 针对你个人吗?
- He sounded pissed. - At you, personally?
就像我跟你说的 他说我羞辱了他
Like I told you, he said I humiliated him
就因为写他咬人是性犯罪
by writing that the biting was sexual.
最后他说要来咬我
At the end, he offered to come here and bite me.
- 我都不知道怎么回应 - 好吧
- I didn't really respond to that. - OK.
- 他听上去是同一个人吗 - 什么意思
- Did he sound like the same guy? - What do you mean?
跟你接到的上一通电话声音相同吗
Did it sound like the voice you heard on the first call?
哦是的 对
Oh, right. Yeah.
老实说不同 呃相同 我是说相同
No, actually. Well, yeah. I mean, yeah.
是同样的声音 但这次我注意到
It was the same, but this time I noticed
他巴尔的摩口音很重 相当重
he had a real thick Bawlmer accent. Real thick.
- 你上次没听出来? - 我想我是听出来又忘了
- You didn't notice that the first time? - I guess I did, but I forgot.
- 我搞砸了吗 - 没有 完全没有
- Did I screw up in any way? - No. Not at all.
听着 我们保留做决定的权利
Listen, we reserve the right to make this decision,
但话虽如此 将这张照片登报
but that said, would running these photos
会从某方面妨碍调查吗
in any way impair the investigation?
我觉得应该不会 老实说  我们需要尽可能多的人
I don't think so. Fact is, we need as many eyes as we can
帮助寻找这个流浪汉
looking for this homeless guy.
你不知道这家伙在哪儿 他可能已经...
You don't know where this guy is? He could be...
- 的确可能已经遇害 - 老天
- Could already be a victim, sure. - Jesus.
那里是Charles街和Conway街附近 不知道他是否常在那周围出现
That's Charles and Conway. I wonder if he's a regular out there.
他肯定用过另一支电话
He had to have used a different phone.
给你发这些图必须得用手机
Had to have been a cell phone if he sent you these.
不错 但再说一次  你们不能公布他打电话的地点
That's true. But, again, you can't print anything about where he's calling from.
我们在尝试窃听那支手机
We're trying to get up on that cell phone.
他要再次打来我该怎么做
What should I do if he calls again?
拖住他别挂 越久越好 别吓着他
Keep him on the line as long as you can. Don't spook him.
这家伙喜欢碎碎念 由着他念
Guy likes to rant. Let him do his thing.
- 你还好吗 - 我? 还行吧
- You OK? - Me? Yeah, I guess.
我觉得不必担心 他只是利用你  他需要你
I wouldn't worry. He's just using you. He needs you.
老实说我对此深恶痛绝
I kind of resent that, actually.
我看未必
Oh, I dunno.
你俩不是都各得其所吗
It's workin' out pretty well for both of you, right?
先生们 多谢了
Gentlemen, thanks for these.
早上打Vincent的电话 他还是没接
Callin' Vincent on his cell all morning, he still ain't answer.
来不及了 补货的日子就要到了
Ain't got time for this. Re-up time will come due,
我们还没拿到甘露醇
we still ain't picked up the mannitol.
搞什么飞机
What the fuck?
喂Vincent
Yo, Vincent.
你在哪儿
Where you at?
Manny Manny
Manny? Manny?
靠
Shit.
- Omar - 那他怎么会留你活口
- Omar. - Why you still alive, then?
他说告诉Marlo 他就在街上等着
He say tell Marlo he out in the streets, waitin'.
说整个城市都会知道
Say this whole damn city gonna know
Marlo根本没种上街
Marlo ain't man enough to come down in the streets.
- 他把货拿走了? - Cherry
- He get the stash? - Yo, Cherry.
他进来就把Manny一枪崩了
He blew Manny up as soon as he got inside.
- 他还想把我也崩了 - 他到底是怎么进来的
- He was gonna do me too. - How the fuck he get inside?
Manny开门去买点吃的
Manny open up to go on the food run,
这死基佬就守在外面
and this dicksucker was right there.
他知道我们是藏毒点
He knew we was the stash.
根本不用多说半句屁话
Ain't need to be told shit.
他就是知道
He just knew.
四公斤纯货 全冲掉了
Four K of raw, flushed.
喂 Cherry 你会把我解开的吧
Hey, yo, Cherry. You gonna untie me, right?
快点哥们 把我解开
Come on, nigga, untie me.
说真的 Steven
Seriously, Steven.
如果你付不起 没关系 我理解
If you can't afford it, that's fine, I understand.
如果你觉得这小丑会霸占着州议会
If you think this clown is gonna hold me off
让我当不成州长  我知道你也会两边下注
and keep the statehouse, I know you've got to hedge your bets
因为安纳波利斯首府那边你已经等了太久
given how much you're waiting on from Annapolis.
但要是你决定选择阵营 早点选 我就这点要求
But if you're gonna choose a side, do it early. That's all I'm saying.
知道了 Tom
I hear ya, Tom.
我今天就会开张支票给你寄去
I'm going to write out a check today, and send it out the door.
那太好了 Steven 真的 我感激不尽
That's great, Steven. Really, I do appreciate it.
你能...
Can you...
能请你考虑下...
Can I ask you to consider...
我会连我老婆那份一起出的
I'll double down on that for my wife too.
连你老婆那份?
For your wife too?
那真是再好不过 真的
That's just great, really.
好的 谢谢你的大方之举
Yeah, thanks for going the extra mile on this.
没问题
No problem.
照片?
Photographs?
他将疑似受害者的数码照片 用短信发给了太阳报记者
He messaged digital photos of the possible victim to the Sun reporter.
我彻查了这家伙的常驻地
I canvassed this guy's regular corner,
他的确已经失踪了好几天
he has indeed been missing a couple of days.
这些照片我们是从报社得来的
We got these photos from the newspaper,
但我们希望能拦截今后的照片
but we want to be able to intercept any future images.
- 因此要修改原协议 - 不错
- Hence the amended order. - Correct.
我们用市警署的设备能拦截到图片吗
Can we catch photos with our city equipment?
老实说不能 我们的设备都是些老古董
Actually, no. We're still bumping around in the 20th century.
但霍华德县警署的几台电脑里
But Howard County has the right software
- 有合适的软件 - 你需要两台?
- on a couple of their computers. - You need two?
对 以防一台电脑出问题  我们还有台可以备用
Yeah. In case one computer goes down, we got the other one as backup.
可不能失手放走这个疯子
We don't wanna miss our shot at this nut.
祝你早日抓到他
Well, good hunting.
谢谢你 法官大人
Thank you, Judge.
Ronnie
Ronnie.
你向你上司作简报没
You briefed your boss?
他正给市长打电话 对不
And he's calling the mayor, right?
我想Rawls也是
And Rawls too, I imagine.
这靓小伙靠宣扬法律秩序拉来的票
Pretty little fella gets himself elected
才当选了市长 犯罪率却没下去多少
on a law-and-order ticket. Crime doesn't go down much,
就在他摩拳擦掌准备竞选州长之前的几周
and a couple weeks before he starts gearing up to announce for governor,
有个疯子突然开始出来大肆杀人
some wingnut starts killing people,
拍照片 发到报社
taking photographs, sending 'em to the newspaper.
知道不 你也许该去查查州长的不在场证明
You know something? You may wanna check the governor's alibi.
知道吗
You know?
多谢
Thanks.
你没筹到3万?
You couldn't make 30?
2万?
20?
9万2
92.
我得告诉你们
I'm gonna tell you something.
有好些人都希望Tommy Carcetti 能当上他们的州长
There are a lot of people want Tommy Carcetti to be their fuckin' governor.
我都不知道他们在想些啥
And I can't imagine what they're thinking.
9万2 Norman 就一个早上 都创纪录了
92, Norman, in a single morning. It is a new record.
那个杀流浪汉的兔崽子  他从街上掳了个流浪汉
The motherfucker killing homeless guys? He grabbed one off the street,
在他手腕上帮了丝带  还发照片给巴尔的摩太阳报
wrapped a ribbon on his wrist, sent a photo to the Baltimore Sun,
- 声称我们绝不会找到尸体 - 什么
- saying we won't find the body. - He what?
报社要登这照片
The newspaper's gonna run the photos.
Bill Rawls 给我马上打给他
Bill Rawls. I need him on the line now.
* 你这无赖 *
* You rascal, you *
* 你死掉我心里就舒坦 *
* I'll be glad when you're dead *
* 你这无赖 *
* You rascal, you *
瞧你这鸟样 你这虐童的王八蛋
Look at you, you baby-bumpin' motherfucker.
社工调查 Micheal Lee   调查结果:无法下定论
瞧你这鸟样
Look at you.
走吧 副局长让我现在把组里
Let's go. Deputy wants as much of my squad
能叫上的人都叫到楼上
as I can wrangle upstairs right now.
McNulty的连环杀手案 Richard想让我们扩大队伍调查
We're going large Richard on McNulty's serial killer.
我在查我的案子
I'm working my cases.
Bunk 御前演出啊
Bunk, command performance.
副局长铁了心要找尸体 市长也倾注心力在这件案子上
The deputy wants bodies. The mayor's spewing over this thing.
我不去
I'm not going.
怎么 你没见我官比你大吗
What? You don't see those on my sleeve?
- 明摆着要听令啊 Bunk - 我这干的才是警察的活
- Plain as fuckin' day, Bunk. - I'm doing police work here.
其实去年的重案我刚找到新的切入点
In fact, I have a fresh angle on last year's major case,
这案子就剩我一个人调查
on which I'm the sole remaining investigator.
去他妈的命令 去他妈的McNulty
So fuck your stripes and fuck McNulty,
去他妈的焦点大案
and fuck your big-dick redball.
你要是觉得不服 就打我报告
If you can't work with that, just write me the fuck up,
告我上法庭
and ship my ass to a trial board.
所以首先让Alma跟市区的调查员和探长联络
So, Alma stays with the investigation and detectives downtown.
必须查了二校和三校前的更新才能回家
Don't go home without checking for updates before the e-dot and double-dot editions.
案子由McNulty负责
So the case file is McNulty,
他组里的其他人作为即时支援
with the rest of his squad as immediate support.
D'Addario警督的轮班警员负责盯着窃听器
Lieutenant D'Addario's shift will man the wiretap.
除Alma和Scott以外 Olesker会开个专栏
In addition to Alma and Scott, Olesker will have a column coming.
Fletcher 我要你去收集流浪汉对此案的看法 还要采访律师和专家的意见
Fletcher, I want you on homeless react, also interviews with advocates and experts.
Melody你给Clifton T. Perkins
Melody, you get on the phone
或别的啥医院的医生打电话
with the whitecoats at Clifton T. Perkins or wherever,
再在侧栏写篇关于疯子杀人
and work up a sidebar on what it means when a whackjob kills somebody
还主动告诉记者这意味着什么的报道
and talks to reporters about it.
Greggs 我一直在查阅案件报告
Greggs, I've been scanning the casework.
尽管进行了大量的实地调查和访谈
While there have been numerous field interviews and canvasses,
我们在受害者背景和家庭调查方面 却没下足功夫
we haven't done much with background work on victims and families.
你去负责这部分
If you could take charge of that.
Tomlin副总警监
Colonel Tomlin,
我们需要战略部提供监控车
we'll need Tactical to provide surveillance cars
还要在流浪汉聚集地安插便衣
and undercover decoys where the homeless gather.
我们要去到街上 主动出击
We need to be in the street, proactive.
逮捕犯人固然重要
This case is as much about preventing another abduction or murder
防止再次发生绑架或谋杀也同样重要
as it is about making an arrest.
重点是 这次蹲在办公室 打打电话是不够的
Thing is, we can't work this one with the phone.
我们要去外面 眼见为实
We need to be in the street, at eye level.
我们要跟媒体合作
We need to keep the media as part of the equation.
这位被凶手联络的记者 他是当事人
This reporter that's been contacted, he's in the middle of it.
也许会是解决这起案件的关键
That may be a way to solve this thing.
你现在是当事人
You're in the middle of this now,
所以尽管我们要以第一人称视角写出
so while we're presenting this as a first-person piece
你此次与凶手的接触的报道
on your latest contact with the killer,
Alma也会在主栏作一篇对你的采访
Alma's going to interview you for the mainbar.
当前McNulty经过对收容所工作人员的初步调查
McNulty's preliminary checks with shelter workers,
以及在Conway街道和Charles街道 彻查表明受害人确实已经失踪
and a canvass of Conway and Charles, indicates that our victim is indeed missing,
但在我们查明受害人身份后
but when we get a full ID,
必须彻查所有跟他有过接触的相关人士 以确保这不是场恶作剧
we need to run every connection to make sure this isn't a hoax.
头儿 我们需要从片警调人手
Chief, we need to pull bodies from District Ops
助凶杀组的实地监视行动一臂之力
to give Homicide their own surveillance arm.
鉴于McNulty曾有过编制队伍的经验
And having had some experience in the politics of staffing,
我将选派人手之事全权交给他负责
I leave it to McNulty to pick the people.
就这次来看 我向大伙儿保证
For once, people, I am assured
有关这次报道所需要的所有信息来源 都等着我们去挖掘
that the resources we need to work this story will be there for us.
所以让我们去其糟粕取其精华 将此事件大肆报道一番
So let's surround this mess and report the hell out of it.
这次肯定会闹得满城风雨
This one's got legs.
市长直接向我表明
I am now told, by the mayor directly,
这件案子没有加班限制和人员限制
that there will be no overtime restrictions, no staffing limits on this case.
所以定要尽快把此案侦破
So put this case down.
这又恢复正常警务了 谁想得到呢
Police work. What do you know?
生意不错 已经卖掉6包粉了
Good day. Six G-packs so far.
新品种简直让他们欲罢不能
New package be droppin' them fiends.
是啊
Yeah.
也许得再补次货
Probably need one more re-up.
- 难得上次街头哈 - 滚开 伙计
- Rare day on the corner, huh? - Step off, nigga.
Mike 瞧这个
Hey, Mike, check this out.
"执照水疗师
"Certified hydrotherapist,
"有照顾老年病人相关工作经验
"experience with geriatric patients,
西奈门诊医院"
Sinai Hospital outpatient clinic."
- 老啥来着 - 随便啦 这个怎么样
- Jerry who? - Whatever, how about this -
"牙科前台
"Dental front desk,
"高级牙科诊所招聘前台"
"high-quality dental office seeks front desk."
- 啥意思 是说的家具么 - 是说的秘书 我猜
- What do you mean? Like furniture? - Like a secretary, I guess.
哥们你都没去看过牙医呢
Man, you ain't even ever been to no dentist.
"采暖通风与空调系统维修主管"
"HVAC maintenance supervisor."
采暖通风什么玩意儿
What the fuck is a huhvac?
"H-V-A-C" 也许他们拼错了吧
"H-V-A-C." Maybe they spelled it bad.
"能面对高压力快节奏工作环境的系统经理"
"Systems manager in a deadline-driven environment."
老兄 那上面都是些没谱的
Man, ain't nothing there.
就算有 你也没满16岁
Even if there was, you ain't 16,
而且你三点之后还得去接Bug放学
and y'all got to pick up Bug after three.
嘿 等等
Hey, hang on, hang on.
"脱衣舞者 市中心金融区 午饭时间工作
"Exotic dancer, downtown financial district lunchtime hours.
"身体柔软 思想开放"
"Must be flexible in body and mind."
这才对嘛
Now we talking.
大爷走过路过 个个出手阔绰
Hey, make it rain on 'em. Make it rain.
- 打住 - 暂停啦
- Hold up. - Time out.
我犯什么事儿了
Fuck did I do?
你心知肚明
If we don't know, then you do.
简直胡说八道
This is bullshit.
喂 别忘了接Bug
Yo, don't forget about Bug.
由于案件仍在调查当中 你们要是有问题请直接问警方
As this is an ongoing investigation, I'll ask that you direct questions
他们能给出最为准确的回答
to the police officials best equipped to answer.
当前市里这起流浪汉残杀案的事态发展
These new developments in the case of the homeless slayings in our city
不仅棘手且不幸 还令人无法容忍
are troubling and tragic and unacceptable.
我们目前正尽一切手段找出寄给
We are doing everything possible to locate and identify the individual
巴尔的摩太阳报的照片中人的位置和身份
depicted in the photographs sent to the Baltimore Sun today.
我们将竭尽全力的保护其他无家可归的市民
We are endeavoring to protect other homeless citizens,
我们将调动所有可用资源 不遗余力的追捕嫌犯
and we are pursuing the suspect with every means at our disposal.
我已经向警部指挥官说明
I have made clear to my police commanders
我信任并授权他们
that they have my full confidence
征用所有行动所需要的资源
and the authority to employ whatever resources they require.
我的态度非常明确
And let me be unequivocal.
凶手必将被绳之以法 谢谢
This man will be brought to justice. Thank you.
市长先生 市长先生
Mr. Mayor, Mr. Mayor!
声音和数码照片
Voice and digital photos.
他要是再打来 你就会截到其中之一
He calls again, you'll capture either one.
我可以自己去做背景调查 Jay 没必要让Greggs去...
I can do these background  checks myself, Jay.??
你也听见副局长说的  他特别指定Greggs去
You heard the deputy. He specifically assigned Greggs.
Greggs手上还有一起三重谋杀
Greggs has an open triple.
这个组里还有你的连环杀手呢 这案子才是重中之重
And this squad has your serial killer. The case is shit-hot.
- Jay 我不需要... - 你是寻找失踪者的主力队员
-Jay, I don't need... -You are the point man on the motherfucker who's missing.
没时间去管那些旧案
You don't have time to work on the older cases.
让Greggs去查 不用他妈的多说了
It goes to Greggs, end of fucking story.
现在 你还需要什么
Now... what else do you need?
等这事传开之后我需要些监视小组
I'm gonna need those surveillance  teams as this thing sprawls.
现在我先尽快查出这人的身份 看看他是个什么人
For now, let me pull this guy's ID as fast as I can. Figure what he's about.
- 在那之后我就能更游刃有余一些 - 要对那通电话进行语音分析吗
- After that, I'll have more to spin off. - Voice analysis of the call?
靠 我不相信这玩意儿
Shit, I don't believe in that shit.
FBI下属的BAU行为分析小组坐落于Quantico
要不了多久你就会让我 为了这该死的案子去Quantico找FBI了
Next thing I know, you'll want me to go to Quantico with this fucking thing.
事实上...
As a matter of fact...
你不相信行为辨析这套吗 Moreland博士
You don't believe in behavioral forensics, Dr. Moreland?
现在我啥都不信了
I don't believe in much of anything at this point.
现在咱们信啥都无所谓
It doesn't fucking matter what any of us believe at this point.
你带来这个窃听的案子 Jimmy
You turned on the fuckin' tap, Jimmy.
他们终于又开始为警务工作付钱了
They're finally paying for police work again.
你志得意满了
Proud of yourselves?
我们就快逮住Marlo的尾巴了  最多还需一到两周
We're close to Marlo. A week or two at most.
害Gregg没法查她的三尸案感觉如何
How does it feel getting Greggs pulled off her triple?
知道会有监视组 片警 和机动小组
How does it feel knowing that  you got surveillance teams out there,
为了你们捕风捉影瞎转悠的感觉如何
and District units, and Tactical, all of 'em chasin' bullshit.
我们用得上监视小组 他们会帮我们立案
We're gonna use the surveillance teams. They'll help us bring in the case, Bunk.
我甚至不想知道报纸上那家伙 是你们从哪儿搞来的
I don't even want to know whose  picture you got running in the paper,
还有他到底消失去了哪里
or where that motherfucker actually happens to be...
名字和地址 你有啥给啥
Names and addresses, whatever you got.
- Jimmy - 小心点别送命
- Jimmy... - Don't kill yourself.
去你的
Shit.
别担心小子 这些就交给我查吧
Don't worry, son. I got you covered on all this.
听着 还有件事
Listen, one other thing.
我要把孩子接过来住一晚
I'm getting my kid for an overnight.
该去哪里给他买家具
Where do I get kids' furniture?
宜家
Ikea.
再会各位
See y'all.
你们可真是厚颜无耻
Shame on y'all.
我说真的
I mean it.
- 迹证实验室 - 我是Moreland
- Trace lab. - It's Moreland.
你刚刚才打过
You just called.
我知道 我就是要再打一次
I know, and I'm callin' again.
我需要06H271案件的迹证分析 现在就要
I need the tracework on 06H271, and I need it now.
我知道 他还没做到这里
I know, he hasn't been around to it yet.
告诉他我打过电话 跟他说我会一直打
Tell him I called, and tell him I'm gonna keep calling
打到他烦死为止 听见没
until he feels my fucking pain, all right?
一份大礼
Gift-wrapped.
去一号审讯室
Number one.
他妈的
Fuck.
就靠我一个人怎么可能把这事搞定
How the fuck do they expect me to get this shit done on my own?
操蛋警局连钱都不给
Broke-ass department ain't even payin'.
你还好吗
You OK?
完蛋 全他妈完蛋了知道吗
It's fucked up. It's all fucked up, OK?
老子啥事儿都能招呼 但就这些狗日的搞不定啊
I could make a red go to black 'cept for these cheap motherfuckers.
你手上是啥案子
What do you got?
我有个很棒的线人好不容易找到了 一直在躲着我的目击证人
Good snitch put the finger on  an eyeball wit been duckin' me.
目击证人住在Athol大道一个女孩家里
He lays up at this one girl's place at Athol Avenue, right?
每天早出晚归
Comes in late, but he leaves early.
那又怎么样
So?
我倒是不介意没有加班费还整晚守在那等
So I don't mind sittin' on the place all night long an' not get paid.
但那是个带花园的公寓 前后都有停车场
But it's a garden apartment. Parking lots on both sides,
而且他要是想把车停在街道上直接从草坪走
and if he decides to park on the street and walk across the grass,
也能从该死的阳台门进去
he still has the fucking patio doors.
需要多派两个人手?
Two more men do it?
是啊 还得多要两辆车
Yeah, and two more cars, yeah.
我的连环杀手案上指给我的人手有余
I got more bodies than I  can use on my serial thing.
让我打个电话 联系两个机动小组的警员帮你
Let me make a call, hook you up with two Tac guys.
你告诉他们你守的地址是我给你的
You tell 'em you're sitting on a 20 that I gave you.
- 我把你的加班时数写进我的文件里 - 你还能这么做?
- I'll write up the hours under my file. - And you can do that?
上帝与你同在
Go with God.
你认得出这是谁么
Can you make out who that is?
是的
Yeah.
看看你
Look at you.
连眼睛都不眨
Not even blinking.
我并不是要怪你  这混蛋对你做过的事十恶不赦
Not that I blame you after what this  heinous motherfucker did to you.
但这仍然是起恶性谋杀
Still, this right here is vicious.
我是说 干这事的人可真是心狠手辣
I mean, whoever did this had a real time.
你懂我意思吗
Now you know what I'm saying?
现在 我知道不是你干的
Now, I know it wasn't you,
恕我直言
because with all due respect
凭你那几两肉没能耐造成这种重伤
you don't have the physicality to do this kind of damage.
犯这事的人必须得是个 已经发育完全的强壮成年人
I mean, whoever did this had to be  a full-grown and powerful individual -
一个看了就让人害怕的人
a fearsome individual.
你懂我意思吗
You see what I'm sayin'?
你才是管谋杀的刑警 我他妈懂什么
You the murder police. How the fuck would I know?
- 这位置适合做单人报道吗 - 这里咱们拍个广角镜头
- Is this spot good for a stand-up? - Let's go with a wide shot on this.
每年媒体报社争抢的新闻行业最高荣誉
该死的普利策奖
Goddamn Pulitzers.
写得有点公式化 我知道
Kinda formula, I know.
轶事式导语 核心段落 引述的良言金句
Anecdotal lead, nut graf, best quote.
作为侧边栏还不错  但明天咱们再多扩展点写
It works as a sidebar,but for  tomorrow, let's stretch it some, huh?
要真的去花时间了解这些人 知道吗
Really spend some time with some of these people, you know?
我的意思是 有时候最薄弱无力的报道
What I mean is, sometimes, the weakest stuff in a story
就是满篇都是引述人家话的
is the shit with quotation marks around it.
你找到个人跟你述说流浪的艰难困苦 并不能激起多少共鸣
You got a guy telling how rough it is on the street, it really doesn't have much pull.
但假如你能详述他到底是个怎样的人 在字里行间写尽他的人生路
But if you can describe him as he  really is, tell his story in moments...
听着 明天回到那个收容所和流动厨房
Look, tomorrow,get back in the  shelters and the soup kitchens,
就跟这哥们相处相处
and just be with folk.
我不在乎你明天是不是 只能交出同样的文章
I don't care if you file copy on it.
我是说  要是在此之中你顺理成章得到个好故事
I mean if something presents itself as a story,
那再好不过 但如果没有得到 那就花一天时间跟这些人相处
great, but if not, just  spend the day being with people.
我不在乎这篇报道有没有什么金句 或是什么有价值的信息
I'm not interested in what can be quoted or counted on this one.
我只在乎真情实感
I'm interested in what feels true.
我搞定了 30英寸的版面 包括Price作的市政厅采访
I'm in - 30 inches, with room for Price's stuff from the hall.
- Scott - 再五分钟
- Scott? - Five minutes.
- 初版时间就要截止了 - 再三分钟
- We're coming up on first edition. - Three minutes.
我们把他送去 那个叫什么来着
We had him in that, what do you call it,
- 康复中心 - 四次
- rehabilitation. - Four times.
我们不是什么有钱人家
We're not rich people.
Henry领着伤残救济金
Henry's on disability.
我们接他出来的时候  他什么事都信誓旦旦的满口答应
We get him out,he  makes all kinds of promises,
但是 你也知道...
but, well, you know...
我很抱歉
I'm sorry.
上次
The last time,
我们决定不再帮助他了
we decided we wouldn't be there for him.
我们知道他很有可能会横尸街头
We knew he'd probably die out there,
假如他是死于毒品 我们也早有心理准备
if the drugs get him, we knew that.
但报纸上写的那些 性犯罪的事
But this thing in the newspaper, this sex stuff,
被咬还是什么的...
the biting or whatever...
上帝啊 没人该遭这种报应啊
Jesus, nobody deserves that.
你们明白我不满的地方吧
You see what I have a  problem with, right?
先不说以第一人称视角来写的问题 我知道他必须把自己也写进报道里
The first-person is one thing. I know he needs to put himself in the story...
这至关重要
It's essential.
但他说自己日夜与流浪汉共处
But this business about him being out there day and night with the homeless,
还说道与他们"共庇于黑漆漆的街头巷角"
I mean, this stuff about sharing their "darkest corners with them,"
他是以更贴近随笔评论的方式写的
He's writing more as an essayist.
咱们已经有Olesker的评论专栏了  就在城市新闻版
We've got a column from Olesker, front metro.
虽然专栏辞藻并不华丽 但却振聋发聩
I mean, it's pretty powerful without being purple.
但Scott写的这些
But this stuff that Scott's written,
说得好像他跟流浪汉共度过好几周似的
it makes it sound like he's been living with the homeless for weeks.
他不过在高架桥下面待了一晚上罢了
He spends one night under the JFX,
还有半天摘录收容所的人说的话
another half-day quoting people in a homeless shelter.
Studs Terkel:美国著名作家 以磁带录音方式采访普通人
又不是Studs Terkel的水准
It ain't exactly Studs Terkel.
你觉得这篇文章不能就这么登报?
You don't think the piece should run as it is?
我是说 在Alma的主栏里已经写了 采访他有关凶手打电话给他的事情
I mean, we have him interviewed about the call from the killer in Alma's mainbar,
我们已经引用了他的口述 但剩下的这些内容
we have his quotes. But the rest of this stuff,
感觉他已经置生死于度外
he's acting like he's taking his life in his hands,
他彻夜沿公路游荡
he walks another highway at night?
这里可是城市 又不是黎巴嫩的贝鲁特
I mean, this is our fucking city. This ain't Beirut.
我尊重你对此的忧虑
I respect your concerns.
这篇文章交给我 就换我作责编如何
I'll take the piece and  move it as my own edit. How's that?
行
OK.
尽管拒绝上镜
And while they declined to talk on camera,
Jonathan Boland的父母说他们希望
the parents of Jonathan Boland say they are hopeful
几年前儿子的死亡在近期引起的强烈关注
that the renewed attention to their son's death a few years ago
能促使警察将凶手捉拿归案
will lead police to his killer.
第六新闻频道报道 我是Cass...
For Channel Six News, I'm Cass...
媒体简直炸成了一锅粥
Media's going crazy.
市政厅也是
City Hall too.
不过这次 我们办案所需终于有求必应了
But for once, we're getting what we need to do the job.
- 这种感觉怎样 - 心虚
- How does it feel? - Forbidden.
感觉他们会发现花费过多 然后让我们全歇了
I feel like they're gonna find out how much we're spending and shut us down.
这些东西你不是早就烂熟于胸了吗
You don't have all this in your head yet?
我只是想再过一遍
I just want to go over it all again.
陪审团预审中午结束 然后就是公开庭辩
We finish voir dire by lunch, and then it's opening arguments.
- 由Bond先生操刀 责任在他 - 他也需要个强力的次席律师
- For Mr. Bond. It's on him. - He needs a strong second.
他要求我对这个案子了如指掌
He needs me to know this case inside and out.
还要多久 Lester
How much longer, Lester?
如果Marlo用了某种暗语  我们就能破解它 这是肯定的
If Marlo has a code, we  can break the code. That's a given.
至于要花多久 这得看是什么暗语是吧
How long? Depends  on the code, doesn't it?
越快把这事搞定收手 我们就越安全
Quicker we bring this in and shut it down, the safer we'll all be.
Landsman想让我去Quantico
Landsman wants me to go to fucking Quantico,
让FBI就犯罪心理为凶手作个侧写
let the FBI do a profile.
也许还能让你更了解自己的内心呢
Might learn something about yourself.
这不好笑 Lester
It's not funny, Lester.
这件事闹得太大 超出了我的想象
This shit's bigger than I ever thought it would be.
整个城市都...
The whole fuckin' city...
Jay 是我
Yeah, Jay.
不
No.
不用 我不需要警校学生
No, I don't need an academy class
去帮助彻查受害者常驻地点
to help with a canvass near this guy's corners.
我不再需要彻查了
Well, I don't need any additional canvassing.
什么 你想知道原因 那我告诉你
What? You wanna know why? I'll tell you why.
因为我已经知道这失踪老毒虫的名字了
Because I already know the name of the missing smokehound.
对 他的姓名 出生日期  还有他最近为人所知的收容所地址
Yeah, his name, his DOB, and his last known address at a city shelter.
Lawrence Butler 1951年3月11日
Lawrence Butler, 3/10/1951,
西街400号 南巴尔的摩收容所
400 West Street, South Baltimore Men's Shelter.
怎么查到的? 警务工作呗
How? Police work.
我查到更多线索以后 警官
When I have more leads, Sergeant,
我就能用上你派给我的额外人手 将凶手捉拿归案了
I'll be able to use the extra manpower you give me and run this shit down.
但在那之前 你少来烦我 Jay
But until then, will you back off, Jay?
对 少他妈来烦我
Yeah, just back the fuck off.
把这案子搞得万众瞩目的麻烦就在于
Trouble with making  this thing into a redball?
还真他妈有万众来随时瞩目着
People start to treat it like a fucking redball.
老天爷
Jesus!
尽快让我脱身 Lester 越快越好
Get me out of this, Lester, as fast as you can.
参议员
Senator!
关于最后关头的认罪协议 大家众说纷纭
Senator, there have been rumors of a last-minute plea offer.
我都没做过的事 怎么可能认罪呢
How can I plead to what I didn't do?
您在看什么书 Senator
What are you reading there, Senator?
这本
This here?
被缚的普罗米休斯 历史戏剧
Prometheus Bound, an ancient play,
最古老的历史剧之一
one of the oldest we have,
讲一个老实人被位高权重之人重惩
about a simple man who was horrifically  punished by the powers
他所犯的弥天罪行不过是 为普通人带来希望之光
that be for the terrible crime of trying to bring light to the common people.
正如作者埃斯库罗斯所言 "好人没好报"
In the words of Aeschylus, "No good deed goes unpunished."
我无法告诉你这些薄薄的书页 抚慰了多少我的心灵之创
I cannot tell you how much consolation   I find in these slim pages.
- 再问个问题 参议员 - 女士们先生们
- One more question, Senator. - Ladies and gentlemen,
我相信今天在法庭上会是我的幸运日 咱们里面见
I do believe I have my day in court, and I will see you inside.
市政厅想知道最新进度  有什么失踪流浪汉的情报吗
City Hall wants an update. What do we know about our missing mope?
还有啥别的
What else?
把电话的录音和案件资料都寄去Quantico了
Sending a tape of the call down to Quantico, along with the case file.
他们会研究研究 然后跟我们会面
They'll review, then meet with us.
你必须把每个市区的收容所都找个遍 或者派人去找
You gotta hit every downtown   shelter or mission there is.
- 你需要谁去吗 - 就选Christeson吧
- You want bodies for that? - I'm taking Christeson.
- 那新手? - 对 他会多问些问题
- The rookie? - Yeah, he'll ask the extra question.
他比较有进取心 他还... 要是我需要跟多人手 会跟你说的
He's hungry. He's... If I need more bodies, I'll let you know.
听说了你帮Christeson干的好事
Heard what you did with Christeson,
让他继续查自己的案子  还借你之便要到了两个监视小组
letting him go on his own case, while you carry him and two surveillance teams.
干得好 Jimmy
Your shit is right, Jimmy.
- 谢了 - 我要请你帮个忙
- Thanks. - So I got another one for ya.
你还记得我查的强奸杀人案吗 博尔顿山街道发生的那起
You remember the rape-murder  I had? Bolton Hill job?
强奸犯的姐夫 去年他啥都不愿跟我说
Brother-in-law of my rapist, last year wouldn't talk to me,
但现在他老婆被捕了
but now, his wife just got collared,
要是她进了监狱 他的孩子就要归福利院了
and if she gets locked up, his kids go to family services,
所以他现在急于跟咱们达成协议
so he's desperate to deal.
问题就在于 他被关押的监狱隶属纽约系统
The problem is, he's in the New York system -
埃尔迈拉 纽堡 这类地方
Elmira, Newburgh, one of those places.
总之 给我辆公路车和路上开销  我就能把案子破了
Anyway, I get a road car and expenses, I can put it down.
Jimmy 他勒死了个20岁的女孩 还把尸体塞在床下
Jimmy, he strangled a 20-year-old, stuffed her under her bed.
好吧 把我的信用卡拿去车辆调配场
OK, give my CC to motor pool.
我会把开销和加班时数算进我的案子里
I'll bury the expenses and the OT in my file.
多谢兄弟
Thanks, brother.
你还真是占山为王了啊
Ain't you the little king of diamonds.
凶杀组
Homicide.
不在 他在外调查 几小时后再打吧
Nah, he's on the street right now. Call back in a couple hours.
我转念一想 觉得还是让Norris 跟我一起去实地彻查 头儿
On second thought, gonna have Norris   with me on that canvass today, boss.
探长 你说的每笔交易
And with every single transaction you've described, Detective,
资金都是走的参议员的私人账户
the money was routed through the senator's personal account
- 再以现金形式取出 - 是的先生
- and then withdrawn as cash. - Yes, sir.
- 总是以相同的数额吗 - 总是完全相同的数额
- Often in the same amounts? - Often the exact amounts,
有的时候会略少  但总是会包含一天的预付金
sometimes slightly smaller amounts, but always within a day of the initial deposit.
谢谢你 Freamon警探
Thank you, Detective Freamon.
法官大人 我没有其他问题了
Your honor, no further questions.
交叉询问 Murphy先生
Cross-examination, Mr. Murphy.
被告方没有问题 法官大人
No questions, your honor.
- 你有编号吗 - 什么
- You got a number? - What?
写在纸上的编号 如果你有编号 我就能给你找个位置
Number on a slip. If you get a number, I might could find you a seat.
- 今天吃的是奶酪通心粉 - 不 我是个新闻记者
- It's mac an' cheese today. - No, I'm a newspaper reporter.
那你不是来这儿吃东西的咯
So you got what to eat, then.
是的 只是来这里看看 跟流浪者们谈谈
Yeah, came down here just to hang out, and get with some homeless people.
怎么每次你们这些人要找流浪汉 都来我们流动厨房这里找
How come whenever y'all be wanting homeless, y'all come to the soup kitchens?
- 你们不放饭给流浪汉吗 - 谁来我们都给
- You don't serve homeless? - Serve everybody.
流浪汉 穷人 还没等到发工钱的人
Homeless, poor folks, workin' people tryin' to make it to a paycheck.
发工资的前一周半个街坊都来了
Shit, half the neighborhood be up here the week before check day.
嘿 你不是...
Hey, you're not...
流浪汉? 不 我住在我姐的地下室里
Homeless?No, I'm down in my sister's basement,
就在Edmondson村那边
over at Edmondson Village.
你想从流浪汉那里问点什么
What you need the homeless to say?
说点凶杀案有关的  最近的专杀流浪汉的连环杀人犯
Talk about the killings. The thing going on with the serial killer.
但总的说来 我只是想写写他们的真实生活
But mostly, I'm just lookin' for a story about what it's like for them.
真实生活
What life is like.
餐风宿雨呗
Hard times out here.
我简直无法想象
I can't imagine.
你想写他们的真实生活对吗
You gonna write a story about what life's like, huh?
- 我叫Bubbles 哥们 - 我是Mike Fletcher
- Bubbles, man. - Mike Fletcher.
继续说说西巴尔的摩篮球慈善机构
Sticking for the moment with the West Baltimore Hoops charity,
你在那里的主要职责是做什么
what were your basic   responsibilities there?
我说不好
I can't rightly say.
但你却以执行董事的身份领着四万块的年薪
Yet you drew $40,000 a year as the executive director.
不 所有的钱都直接还给了参议员Davis
No. All that money went straight back to Senator Davis.
什么 你一个子都没得
What, none for you?
我是从地方行政办公室那里领着 当他司机的薪水
I got paid through the district   office for drivin' him.
那些钱我自己留着  还有的时候我去外面
That money I kept. An' whenever I  would go out to snatch some money
- 帮参议员抢来的钱 - 反对
- for the senator... - Objection.
- 他有时候会赏我点回扣 - 把刚才那句的记录都消除
...he'd sometimes kick me back a few. - Move to strike all of that.
同意 请陪审团忽略以上言论
Sustained.Disregard that last comment.
本案仅限于对参议员Davis非法运营
This case is limited to the charges stemming from
非盈利慈善机构提出控告
the operation of Senator Davis's nonprofit charities.
其他无关问题不在本案讨论范围内
Other matters are not relevant.
拨出号码 41095078
来了
Here it is.
那是什么鬼东西 5点50分见面?
What the hell is that? A meet at 5:50?
我去查查Monk在干嘛
I'm gonna go get up on Monk.
你曾有过犯罪记录  对不对 Price先生
You have a criminal history, do you not, Mr. Price?
是的 我服过几年刑
Yeah, I did some years.
你上次出狱是六年前
And when you last got out of prison six years ago,
当时Davis参议员知道你有前科吗
was Senator Davis aware of your criminal record?
是的 先生
Yes, sir.
但他还是给了你份工作
And yet he gave you a job,
但今时今日  你就是用这样的行为回报他的吗
but today, is this how you repay him?
你作证说你从参议员的慈善组织得到的钱
The testimony you gave about returning   the money you earned at the senator's charities,
都全数以现金还给了参议员 对吗
you say you repaid it to the senator in cash, correct?
每次都是
Every time.
所以没有任何证据表明 参议员曾收到过那笔钱
So there's no proof that the senator ever received that money.
- 对不对 - 我想是没有
- Isn't that correct? - I guess not.
- 你想是没有 - 我想是没有
- You guess not. - I guess not.
Price先生 你之前承认  作为本次作证人的交换
Mr. Price, you acknowledged earlier that in exchange for your testimony,
你将被豁免本案与你相关的所有指控
you received immunity from prosecution  for any charges related to this case.
是不是可以这么说  作出对Davis参议员不利的证明
Is it fair to say that testifying against Senator Davis
能确保你自己不会坐牢
ensures that you will not yourself go to jail?
- 太他妈对了 - Price先生
- Goddamn right. - Mr. Price.
我是说...操 抱歉
I'm s... Oh, shit, sorry.
- Price先生 - 好的是我不对 法官 抱歉
- Mr. Price. - OK, my B, Judge. Sorry.
Price先生 难道你指望这些陪审
Mr. Price, do you expect this jury
听信你这个两次被定罪的重犯
to take the word of a twice-convicted felon
而不相信人民投票选出的马里兰州议员吗
over the word of a duly elected member of the Maryland state senate?
我能说什么
What can I say?
你们想怎么地就怎么地吧 只要别找我麻烦
Y'all can play it like you feel an' leave me be.
- 怎样 - 是我
-Yeah?  -Yeah.
我被搞糊涂了 他一直站在原地 一个半小时没挪过地儿
I don't get it. He hasn't moved off this spot for an hour and a half.
好吧 那你先回来行不
All right, well, come on back, then, all right?
大伙每三四天就去扫次公共汽车候车室
Guy's been hitting the bus shelters every third or fourth night.
那里从12月开始已经发现两人受伤一人死亡
We got two wounded and one dead going back to that piece since December.
我就需要加班加点的监视着那里 把这个混球抓出来
All I'm asking is for hours to stake this asshole out.
大伙都想要加班费
Guy's like clockwork.
派我和Garvey去守三个晚上
Spot me an' Garvey three nights,
这案子就大功告成
and the case is fuckin' down.
- 我给你两个晚上 - 要是他第三晚才行动呢
- I can give you two nights. - If he hits on the third?
- 一个晚上 - 好吧好吧 两晚就两晚
- One night. - OK, OK. Two nights.
把我的信用卡号写在加班申请条里
You need to put my CC number on the OT slips
- 然后交给Jay - 没问题 我懂这套
- and you give those to Jay... - It's cool. I know the drill.
- 你懂 - 你这是在干好事啊 头儿
- You do? - You're doing good here, boss.
你刚刚叫我什么来着
What did you just call me?
- 这是什么玩意儿 - 警务报告
- What the hell is that? - Office reports.
你那些受害者的家属 全部汇报完毕
Families of your victims, debriefed in full.
相信我 整周的心情都给听毁了
And believe me, it ruined my week.
- 挺艰难的是吧 - 我得坐那儿
- Rough, huh? - I'm sittin' there explaining
给这些疾苦百姓解释为什么
to the salt of the fuckin' earth why their eldest,
由于他们没能帮上儿子的忙 导致他四处流浪无家可归
who is living on the street because nothing they did could fix his problems,
但天可怜见他们真的尽力了
but God knows they tried,
那为什么他还是被个变态佬用来泄欲
why he met his end being bit on and fucked with by some sick motherfucker
被撕咬凌虐不得善终
who used him for jerk-off purposes.
咬痕这事最开始是怎么见报的啊
How the shit about the bite marks get in the papers in the first place?
得走了 还得去组装那破玩意儿
Gotta run. I got shit to assemble.
你可没跟我说过还有这茬 是吧混蛋
You didn't tell me that part of it, did you, motherfucker?
我的天
Jesus...
那个可怜的家伙
that poor guy.
想收留他回家?
Wanna take him home with you?
- 靠 不如收留我吧 - 什么
- I mean, shit, take me. - What?
跟你开玩笑呢 哥们
Just having fun with you, man.
谢谢你带我来这里 老兄  领我到处转转
Thanks for bringing me here, man, showing me around.
不 不是为了钱
Nah. Not about that.
你确定
Sure?
你怎么想的就怎么写吧
Just... write it like it feels.
妈的
Fuck.
我操
Shit!
Rodney 你不能逼常客把账单都结清
Rodney, you can't press a regular for his whole tab.
这不是办法
It just isn't done.
我以前也是开酒吧的  这方面我是老鸟 记得吗
I used to run a bar. I know how these things work, remember?
- Gus Haynes大驾光临啊 - 待会再拍我马屁吧
- Gus Haynes in the flesh. - Well, more of it, maybe.
你最近怎么样 都躲哪儿去了 你还在缉捕队当差吗
How you been? Where you been hidin'? You in Vice still?
缉捕队 那都是多久以前了
Vice? Shit, that does take me back.
我在凶杀组干了8年 老兄 现在在西区当巡警
I did eight years in Homicide, brother. Now it's the Western.
说到躲起来 你都多久没来看看了 上次我见你还是在...
Speaking of hiding out, when did you stop comin' round? Last I saw you was...
我后来没在到处跑新闻了  我当了编辑 所以...
I'm not running the districts anymore. I'm an editor now, so...
那你就请得起大伙喝一轮啦
Then you can afford to buy a round.
嘿 Dennis
Hey, Dennis.
咱们叙叙旧
Let me pull your coat.
好久不见 Gus  别跟我说你早料到我今晚会来
Long time, Gus. Don't tell me you knew I'd be here tonight.
这吧里来的都是警察 要是你没来
It's a cop bar, you know, so, if it's not you,
也能遇上几个旧人
it's some other face from back in the day.
- 问你个假设的问题 - 假设的
- Theoretical question. - Theoretical?
这样Gus就得买两轮 Rodney
In that case, a double, Rodney - Gus is buyin'.
上两轮 Rodney
Two, Rodney.
是这样...
So...
怎么...
What?
我看见你去了藏毒点
I seen you at the stash house, yo.
你以前不是跟着Barksdale混的吗
Ain't you used to be with them Barksdale boys?
- 他们怎么叫你来着 - Savino
- What they call you, yo? - Savino.
这就对了 Savino
That's right. Savino.
你从来不是干运毒这活的
You ain't never moved no dope.
我记得你一直是打手
You was always muscle as I recall.
现在你当Marlo的打手了是吧
Now you musclin' for Marlo, huh?
我不在那里
I wasn't there.
他们干掉老爷子的时候 我不在现场
When they did the old man like that, I wasn't there.
Chris和Snoop 是他们干的
Chris an' Snoop, they on that.
我知道是谁干的 所以你是无辜的咯
I know who was there. So you innocent, huh?
那我问你个问题 老弟
Let me ask you somethin' though.
既然你是Marlo的打手
Bein' that you muscle for Marlo,
要是你当时在现场会怎么做
what you was gonna do if you was there, huh?
给我说说看
Riddle me that.
我想也是
Yeah.
不如这样吧
You know what, yo?
- 你刚听见枪声了吗 - 我靠
- Did you hear a gunshot? - Shit.
准备好了
Ready?
是的
Yeah.
好吧
A'ight.
什么事
Yeah?
- 我们得谈谈 - 我来找你
- We got to talk. - I'll come over to you.
这有可能办到吗
Does that seem possible?
用假身份瞒过法院体系
To go through the court system with a false ID?
第一次还有可能 假如她没有前科  她的指纹没有入档的话
Maybe the first time, if she's got no priors, no prints on file,
在那之后呢
but after that?
出生体质格上有指纹特征 就像FBI的条形码
BPI sheets have fingerprint characteristics that are like an FBI bar code.
并且还有配套的照片
And it's paired with a photo.
名字是一回事 但除非这她们是双胞胎
A name's one thing, but unless these women are twin sisters
而且其中一位还接济另一位的生活12年
and one's been carrying the other one's hand around in her purse for the last 12 years...
不然就是有人在糊弄你
Somebody's yanking your chain.
这绝对是种暗号
It's definitely a code.
肯定跟时间没多大关系
Definitely not having much to do with time.
当前关头我需要更多人手
We're at a point where I'm going to need more bodies,
监视车 加班时间
surveillance cars, man-hours.
我们要一直盯着这些家伙的动向 直到弄明白这些钟表图都是怎么回事
We're gonna have to stay on these guys 'til those clocks start to make sense.
好消息是上面派下来的人手绰绰有余
Good news is they're giving me more manpower than I can waste.
坏消息是
Bad news?
办公室里到处再流传 说我大派工时和加班费
It's all around the office that I'm giving out hours and money
给他们办自己的案子
to people to work other cases.
我身不由己啊 Lester 我就是这种人
I can't help it, Lester. It's the kind of person I am.
- 我一直给得停不下手 - 如果你不小心点
- I give and give. - If you're not careful,
就是在引火烧身 烧咱们俩
you're gonna get shit on you, on us.
谁会去抱怨呢
Who's gonna complain?
大伙都实实在在查自己的案子 而且又有加班费拿
Guys are working cases and getting paid.
所以你到底需要什么
So what exactly do you need?
七个人
Seven men.
不 八个 还有车
No, eight. And cars.
糟糕 他们提供给我用的是片警
Oh, shit, they offered me men from the districts,
还有个监视主管负责特别小组
and a surveillance supervisor to run the detail.
片警里有我们能信任的人吗
Anyone in the districts we trust?
我考虑看看
Let me think on that.
什么事
Yeah?
我不知道你们是怎么把这破玩意组装好的 怎么做的
I don't know how the fuck did you of all people do this shit, huh? How?
- 你扳手用对了吗 - 该死的说明书
- You got the right Allen wrench? - Goddamn directions.
你用的是哪种透明胶
What kind of Scotch you using?
你大爷的
Fuck!
靠 靠
Fuck! Fuck!
垃圾玩意
Piece of shit!
你跟Chris谈过了吗 他怎么说的
Yo, so you talked to Chris, right? What he say?
他啥都没说
He didn't say shit.
他知道我什么都不会对条子说
He knows I ain't say a fuckin' word to no police.
你听说小Dermell 跟少管所教官说什么了吗
And you heard what Little Dermell said to the juvenile master?
女士这样问他 "你有前科吗"
Lady ask him like, "Yo, you got a record?"
他说"是啊婊子 老子有前科
He's like "Yeah, bitch, I got a record.
"老子的前科多得都可以发专辑了"
"My record's so long I'm about to put out an album."
把手拿开 小子
Don't touch that dial, young 'un.
这是Stanfield的地盘 是吧
This a Stanfield corner, huh?
你们知道我是谁吗
You know who I am?
你记住跟你老大说清楚
You make sure you tell the boss man
说你知道是谁昨晚干掉了Savino
that you know who it is dropped Savino last night.
听懂了吗
You feel me?
告诉他我要把他的打手全部干掉
You tell that man I'm-a drop all his muscle
直到他够胆上街来走走
until he get the heart to come down to the street and dance.
你记住了吗 小子
You gonna remone that, sweetpea?
那就是Omar 靠
That's Omar? Damn.
Savino死了吗
Savino dead, yo?
该死 要是那晚我去了Monk的公寓
Shit, man, if he woulda made me from Monk's apartment the other night,
现在死的就是我了
I might be laid out my own self.
他妈的死瘸子
Gimpy as a motherfucker.
我不知道 参议员 我想要相信你
I don't know, Senator. I want to believe you.
我毕竟是你的律师
I mean, I'm your lawyer.
但Bond先生在这板上可是写得清清楚楚
But there's all this up on the board that Mr. Bond has on display -
1万1千块汇入西区篮球慈善基金
11,000 to West Side Hoops,
第二天 1万1千块提现取出
next day, $11,000 drawn,
然后这1万1又进入了你的私人账户
then $11,000 deposited in your personal banking account.
当然进了我的私人账户
You bet it all went into my account.
这样我的工作更顺手
It made it easier for me to do my job.
最后一分钱都没进到我的口袋
And at the end of the day, not one penny stayed with me.
你得说得更明白点 参议员
I need you to do better than that, Senator.
- 你的明细记录呢 - 明细
- Where are your records? - Records?
是的 明细
Yes, records.
比如 这张1月22日开出的1万1千块的支票
For example, this check for $11,000 dated January 22nd.
那是今年冬天的时候 对吧
That was last winter, right?
有的拿去付给了巴尔的摩电气
So, some went to pay everyone's BGE,
因为我那片地方有一半的人的暖气都被停了
'cause half my district was gonna have the heat turned off,
还有的用来买了夹克衫 送给了那些家里小孩要的
and then, some went for puff jackets for them that got children in need.
我告诉你吧
Let me tell you something, man.
在我们那片地方 穷乡僻壤
My neck of the woods, it's a jungle out there.
大家都一贫如洗 勉强凑合着过
Everybody living hand to mouth, improvising, hustlin',
拿着你们难以想象的低收入糊口
make do with as little as you can imagine.
有个电视节目 叫什么来着 幸存者
Hell, that TV show, what's that, Survivor?
他们要是想找点顽强的选手 就得到我们西区来
Man, they want some good contestants, they need to come around westside.
我认识的那些家伙们  肯定都能在那节目上大放异彩
Folks I know? We'd do great on that show.
每天都在这艰苦的条件下练习着
Practice every damn day of our lives.
更不用说谁敢来挑战了
Hell, and Fear Factor?
我都不用再多提了
Don't even get me started.
抱歉 但我还是不明白这如何能证明你...
Forgive me, but I still don't understand how that justifies...
我跟你说吧 老兄
Let me tell you something, brother -
罗兰公园位于巴尔的摩较繁荣的商业街
我不知道他们罗兰公园那边是什么情况
I don't know how they do it out in Roland Park.
也许检察官Obonda能好好教教我
Maybe Prosecutor Obonda can enlighten me on that.
但在我生活的地方都是现金交易 而我是Clay Davis
But my world is strictly cash-and-carry, and I am Clay Davis -
我的人民有什么需要的话 他们知道去哪儿找我
my people need something, they know where to find me.
告诉你吧 老兄 我出门在外
Let me tell you, brother, I step out the door,
走到Pennsylvania大道 和Mosher街的时候
hit the corner of Mosher and Pennsylvania,
肯定口袋还是满满的
you better believe my pockets are bulging.
但当我走到Robert街的时候
But by the time I get to Robert Street...
反对 反对 法官大人
Objection! Objection, your honor.
参议员 参议员 请坐下
Senator! Senator, take a seat,
还有请克制对Bond先生的攻击性言辞
and refrain from off-hand references to Mr. Bond.
抱歉 法官大人
My apologies, your honor.
但这些慈善机构当初是为了
But these charities were set up for basketball leagues
市里休闲中心举行的篮球联赛而建的 对吗
in city rec centers, weren't they?
是倒是 但你捐给我2万块就为了 买个篮球和打气筒
Yeah, but you give me 20,000 for a basketball and an air pump,
我可是有效利用那些钱  为无论何时何地向我求援的人们提供帮助
I am pullin' goodly on that for whatever, whoever comes at me.
"Clay议员 我要为母亲下葬
"Senator Clay, I gots to bury my mother,
"要保释我儿子
"bail out my son,
"要为了工作面试买件新衬衫
"buy a new shirt for a job interview,
"要付钱给我孩子的哮喘病医生"
"pay my child's asthma doctor."
我走个一百码都得被耗上半小时
Takes me half an hour to go a hundred yards,
抱歉我没有向那位 有关节炎的老妇要收据
and excuse me if I didn't ask that old arthritis woman for a receipt,
没有让那位只想要袋奶粉的 年轻妈妈签字画押
or that young mother needed the Similac to sign a damn piece of paper
要是我这么做了  今天就不会坐在这被告席上
so I don't have to be up here in this box right now
向你们这些从没去过我们那带的人
explainin' to folks who never been in our neck of the woods
解释事情的真相
how things truly are.
如果陪审员们
And if a jury of my peers, you all,
你们认为我应该以正义无罪之身
deem it right and true for me to walk out of here
从这里走出去
an upright and justified man?
我实话实说
I ain't gonna lie to you.
今后我仍然会日复一日
I'm gonna do the same damn thing tomorrow,
年复一年的做这些善举
and the day after that and the day after that,
直到我死后躺在三月殡仪馆
until they got me laid out at March's Funeral Home,
被载往奥本山公墓埋葬
and truck me off to Mount Auburn.
肃静
Silence.
法庭内保持肃静
Silence in this courtroom.
FEMA:联邦紧急事务管理局
拖车怎么样 就像FEMA那样
What about trailers? Like FEMA.
我们把拖车布置成临时居所 提供给...
We set up trailers to act as temp housing for some of the...
提供给收容所里的人  将他们安置在战争纪念广场
some of the shelter population. Put 'em down in War Memorial Plaza.
你知道一辆拖车FEMA得付多少钱吗
Do you know how much FEMA pays per trailer?
得要一打拖车才够运流浪者
A dozen trailers for the homeless.
露宿街头的至少有三四千
We've got three to four thousand on the streets, at least.
这只是个象征性意义的举动 表现出我们竭尽全力
It's symbolic. You know, we're doing what we can
为避免全民受累 就像新奥尔良那样
with a civic disaster - like New Orleans.
被州政府抛弃 被联邦政府无视
Abandoned by the state, ignored by the federal government.
你让市里的收容所都每天24小时开门 就已经够糟糕了
It's bad enough you want to keep the city shelters open 24/7.
这会给卫生部增加好几万赤字
That puts the health department a couple hundred thousand in the red.
还要加上警局正疯狂增加的
Add that to the overage for letting the police department run wild
- 加班费和调查成本... - 现在别无选择
- with overtime and investigative costs... - There's no choice anymore.
大家都关注着这案子
This thing has a lock on everyone's attention.
要是再出现一个失踪的受害者  我们会更被推上风口浪尖
When another victim disappears, we're gonna be even more on the spot.
我就是想告诉你 如果这事拖过一个月 以我们现在花钱的速度
I'm just telling you, if this goes on more than a month, with what we'll be spending,
就得面临所有机构全面裁员的危机
you're looking at cutbacks throughout the agencies,
也许在财政年末还得裁老师
maybe even teacher layoffs come the end of the fiscal.
- 裁老师 - 州长候选人裁老师
- Teacher layoffs? - By a gubernatorial candidate.
- 而且就在选举年 - 这下好了
- In an election year. - Lovely.
冷静 冷静各位
Hold up, hold up.
我想说尽管有那么多对我的错误指控
I just want to say that despite all the false accusations made against me,
我效力的人民眼睛是雪亮的
the people who I continue to serve have spoken.
刚刚到底发生了什么
What the fuck just happened?
...只要我继续服务于民
...as long as I can to serve the people.
不管刚刚怎么回事  反正法学院可没教过这个
Whatever it was, they don't teach it in law school.
45寸版面关于Clay Davis不但大打种族牌
45 inches of Clay Davis playing not just the race card,
还大获全胜的报道 现在发给你
but the whole deck, coming at ya.
收到 谢谢
Got it. Thank you.
哪天你得跟我解释下这都怎么回事 Gus
Someday you're going to have to explain all this to me, Gus.
在看了裁决结果之后  我感觉自己有点种族歧视了
After watching that verdict come in, I feel very white.
先听点James Brown的专辑再慢慢学起吧
Well, start with some James Brown records and work up from there.
真丢人 是吧
It's embarrassing, ain't it?
我不敢相信竟然没人理智到把这篇报道压下去
I can't believe nobody had sense enough to tone this down.
炒作就已经够糟糕了  最让我闹心的是我无法相信这家伙
The hype is bad enough, but what gets me is that I can't trust the guy.
我让他回街上去纠正自己的错误
I send him back out on the street to own his mistake,
他回来给我乱扯一通身份被盗用什么的
he comes back with some bullshit about stolen identities.
我不介意他偶尔添油加醋  大家都会有错上加错的时候
I don't give a fuck he gets took. Everybody gets took now and then.
- 反正我这么干过 - 我介意的是他不承认错误
- I know I did. - It's about not owning up to it.
Gus 这个吃了青蟹的女人的故事
Gus, this thing with the woman and the crab cake?
这是你第一次发现  但你觉得这是他首次胡来吗
You think the first time you catch him is the first time he does it?
大部分人都会赶紧修正自己的错误
A lot of guys'll try to duck a correction,
但他在明摆着的谎言面前还理直气壮 如果他连纠正错误都要撒谎...
but he was standing on an outright lie, and if he'll lie about a correction...
那他会不会为了让故事好看些而胡编乱造呢
Then will he lie to make a story better than it ought to be?
我老是在想那个金莺公园外坐轮椅的小孩
I keep thinking about that kid in the wheelchair out in front of Oriole Park.
只有外号的那个小孩
The one that only had a nickname.
来自西区的黑人孩子 疯狂痴迷棒球
A black kid from the westside, crazy for baseball?
篮球说得通
Basketball, yeah.
橄榄球也行
Football, sure.
我不想再断言哪个记者是骗子了
I don't wanna call another reporter a liar.
真的不想
I really don't.
怎么了 宝贝
What's the matter, baby?
你睡不着吗
You can't sleep?
咱们看看啊
Let's see.
咱们对大家都道声晚安吧
Let's say good night to everybody.
晚安月亮
Good night, moon.
- 你来说 - 晚安月亮
- You say it. - Good night, moon.
这就对了 晚安星星
There you go. Good night, stars.
晚安星星
Good night, stars.
- 晚安警警 - 晚安警警
- Good night, po-pos. - Good night, po-pos.
- 晚安坏蛋 - 晚安坏蛋
- Good night, fiends. - Good night, fiends.
- 晚安毒贩 - 晚安毒贩
- Good night, hoppers. - Good night, hoppers.
- 晚安小偷 - 晚安小偷
- Good night, hustlers. - Good night, hustlers.
- 晚安骗子 - 晚安骗子
- Good night, scammers. - Good night, scammers.
- 晚安各位 - 晚安各位
- Good night to everybody. - Good night to everybody.
大家都晚安
Good night to one and all.